Vida Chenoweth collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
Guides to the Collections in the Archive of Folk Culture
Vida Chenoweth collection 1940-2000
AFC 1994/003
Vida Chenoweth, 1929-
15,686 items
42 containers
15.5 linear feet (31 containers).
638 sound cassettes: analog.
251 sound tape reels: analog; various sizes.
89 sound discs: analog; various sizes.
2 sound discs (CD-R): digital; 4 3/4 in.
71 videocassettes (VHS and U-Matic): color, sound; 1/2 in and 3/4 in.
5 videodiscs (DVD).
10 film reels.
approximately 660 photographs: film negatives.
approximately 1200 photographic prints: black and white, color; various sizes.
730 slides; color; 35 mm.
1177 half frame slides, mostly color.
3 slides; color; 126.
Archive of Folk Culture, American Folklife Center, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Collection of papers and audiovisual materials representing the life work of ethnomusicologist Vida Chenoweth. Manuscripts, sound recordings, photographs, and films mainly of her work with the Usarufa and numerous other people in Papua New Guinea, but culture groups from other places are also represented, including Vanuatu, Indonesia, Solomon Islands, Cook Islands New Zealand, Kenya, Zaire, Ethiopia, Madagascar, Ivory Coast, Ghana, South Africa, Cameroon, Senegal, Nigeria, Sierra Leone, Mali, Cameroon, Vietnam, Thailand, Laos, Cambodia, Mexico, Guatemala, Panama, Ecuador, Brazil, Peru, and the United States. Includes work done by her students at Wheaton College and colleagues at the Summer Institute of Linguistics. Includes recording logs, analysis, song transcriptions, song texts, theses, correspondence, Chenoweth's diaries (1980s), and field notes. Sound recordings include music and spoken word from various provinces in Papua New Guinea, such as Eastern and Western Highlands, Madang, Morobe, East New Britain, New Ireland, and Irian Jaya provinces. Moving images include Chenoweth family films, as well as documentation about music and practices from throughout Papua New Guinea, the Cook Islands, Vanuatu, and other regions. They also include content from the South Pacific Festival of the Arts in Port Moresby, Papua New Guinea.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Bee, Darlene Laverne; Chenoweth, Vida; Chenoweth, Vida--Ethnomusicological collections.; Tracey, Hugh
Organizations
Festival of Pacific Arts (3rd: 1980: Port Moresby, Papua New Guinea)
Subjects
Arapaho Indians--Interviews.; Cheyenne Indians.; Church music.; Comanche Indians.; Dance.; Indians of North America--Southwest, New--Languages.; Kiowa Indians.; Language and languages--Papua New Guinea.; Music--Australia.; Music--Brazil.; Music--Cameroon.; Music--Central America.; Music--Congo (Democratic Republic); Music--Cook Islands.; Music--Côte d'Ivoire.; Music--Ethiopia.; Music--Hawaii.; Music--Indonesia.; Music--Kenya.; Music--Liberia.; Music--Madagascar.; Music--Mexico.; Music--New Zealand.; Music--Nigeria.; Music--Papua New Guinea.; Music--Peru.; Music--Philippines.; Music--Senegal.; Music--Solomon Islands.; Music--Southeast Asia.; Music--Vietnam.; Ojibwa Indians--Interviews.; Rites and ceremonies--Papua New Guinea.; Rites and ceremonies.; Songs, Usarufa--Papua New Guinea.; Songs--Texts.; Songs.; Tewa Indians.; Tiwa Indians.; Usarufa (Papua New Guinean people)--Music.; Usarufa language--Papua New Guinea.
Places
Papua New Guinea--Languages.; Papua New Guinea--Social life and customs.; Southeast Asia.; Southwest, New.
Form/Genre
Academic theses.; Amateur films.; Diaries.; Documentary films.; Field notes.; Field recordings.; Hymns.; Manuscripts.; Photograph albums.; Photographs.; Songs.; Sound recordings.; Video recordings.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: I. Manuscripts; II. Sound Recordings; III. Graphic Materials; IV. Moving Images.
Acquisition
Vida Chenoweth; 1996.
Custodial History
Received from Vida Chenoweth, Enid, O.K., in a number of installments beginning in 1994.
Accruals
No further accruals are expected.
Access and Restrictions
Collection is open for research; access to collection materials may be restricted. To request materials, please contact the Folklife Reading Room at http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/folklife.contact
Biographical Note
Vida Chenoweth (b. 1929), is considered the first solo classical concert marimbist, and is known for her career as a marimba artist, as well as a linguist and ethnomusicologist. She served as a linguist and Bible translator in Papua New Guinea, where she worked with colleague, Darlene Bee, analyzing the Usarufa language, teaching Usarufa people to read, and recording their music. Chenoweth devised a method of ethnic music analysis during her years recording and studying Usarufa music. She has authored several books and academic journal articles on ethnic oral music traditions, and she developed the ethnomusicology program at Wheaton College Conservatory of Music based on her theories and analyses of ethnic music. Chenoweth and her ethnomusicology students documented the music and practices of cultures across Papua New Guinea, Africa, South and Central America, and the Southwest United States.
Scope and Content
Collection of papers and audiovisual materials representing the life work of ethnomusicologist Vida Chenoweth. Manuscripts, sound recordings, photographs, and films mainly of her work with the Usarufa and numerous other people in Papua New Guinea, but culture groups from other places are also represented, including Vanuatu, Indonesia, Solomon Islands, Cook Islands New Zealand, Kenya, Zaire, Ethiopia, Madagascar, Ivory Coast, Ghana, South Africa, Cameroon, Senegal, Nigeria, Sierra Leone, Mali, Cameroon, Vietnam, Thailand, Laos, Cambodia, Mexico, Guatemala, Panama, Ecuador, Brazil, Peru, and the United States. Includes work done by her students at Wheaton College and colleagues at the Summer Institute of Linguistics. Includes recording logs, analysis, song transcriptions, song texts, theses, correspondence, Chenoweth's diaries (1980s), and field notes. Sound recordings include music and spoken word from various provinces in Papua New Guinea, such as Eastern and Western Highlands, Madang, Morobe, East New Britain, New Ireland, and Irian Jaya provinces. Moving images include Chenoweth family films, as well as documentation about music and practices from throughout Papua New Guinea, the Cook Islands, Vanuatu, and other regions. They also include content from the South Pacific Festival of the Arts in Port Moresby, Papua New Guinea. LOC numbers and original identifiers listed below reflect the donor, Vida Chenoweth’s, numbering system. Contact reference staff for more information.
LOC numbers and original identifiers listed below reflect the donor, Vida Chenoweth’s, classification system to uniquely identify each geographic area and culture group. This classification system was applied to an earlier classification system that Chenoweth developed to track her collection of sound recordings and moving images. In this system, the format is identified by letter, then by year, and then separated by a slash and followed by a number indicating its chronology in the collection. Chenoweth’s LOC classification system references her sound recording and moving image classification system. Contact reference staff for more information.
Container List
- Series I: Manuscripts
  - LOC 1, 1972 (Box-folder 1/1)
    Collection contents. Sound Recording Log. All sound recordings corresponding to LOC 1-17. Music of the Usarufa language group, Eastern Highlands Province of Papua New Guinea.
  - LOC 2, 1971 (Box-folder 1/2)
    Sound Recording Log. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands, Ukarumpa.
  - LOC 3, 1958-1968, r60/202, r69/215, r58/216 (Box-folder 1/3)
    Sound Recording Log. Music of the Usarufa language group. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands Province.
  - LOC 4, 1966-1969, r66/219, r66/220 (Box-folder 1/4)
  - LOC 5, r66/235 (Box-folder 1/5)
  - LOC 6, 1966, r66/236, r66/237, r66/238r66/239, r66/240, r66/241 (Box-folder 1/6)
    Content list of sound recordings. Music of the Usarufa language group. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands Province.
  - LOC 7, 1967, r67/234 (Box-folder 1/7)
  - LOC 8, 1966, r66/242, r66/243, 266/244, r66/245 (Box-folder 1/8)
    Sound Recording Log. Music of the Usarufa language group. Diary excerpt December 28, 1966. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands Province.
  - LOC 9, 1962-1969, r66/247, r67/366, r66/372, r66/373a, r66/373b, r66/374a, r66/374b, r66/375a, r66/375b, r66/376a, r66/376b, r62/385, r62/386, r72/387, r65/388, r66/389 (Box-folder 1/9)
  - LOC 10, 1966-1967, r66/390, r66/393, r66/394, r67/203 (Box-folder 1/10)
  - LOC 11, 1968, r69/204 (Box-folder 1/11)
  - LOC 12, 1967-1969, r68/205, r67/206, r67/217, r67/218, r67/221 (Box-folder 1/12)
    Sound Recording Log. Transcription of events on corresponding sound recording, song classifications. Music of the Usarufa language group. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands Province.
  - LOC 13, 1967-1968, r68/207 (Box-folder 1/13)
    Sound Recording Log. Includes song text analysis. Music of the Usarufa language group. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands Province.
  - LOC 14, 1968, r68/208, r66/209, r68/210, r68/211, r 68/212 (Box-folder 1/14)
    Sound Recording Log. Includes song text analysis. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands Province.
  - LOC 15, 1967-1968, r67/362, r67/363, r69/359, r68/360, r69/361r68/364 (Box-folder 1/15)
  - LOC 16, 1959-1983, r69/365, r68/357, r59/356, r69/214, c84/416 (Box-folder 1/16)
  - LOC 17, 1969, r69/213 (Box-folder 1/17)
    Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands Province.
  - LOC 18 (folder 1 of 15), 1957-1970 (Box-folder 1/18)
    Map of SIL Language Programs. Usarufa language group. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands Province.
  - LOC 18 (folder 2 of 15), 1967-1971 (Box-folder 1/19)
    Sound Recording Log. Description of events on the corresponding sound recording, song text analysis. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands Province, Usarufa.
  - LOC 18 (folder 3 of 15), 1991 (Box-folder 1/20)
    Letter from Vida Chenoweth about Christian education in Papua New Guinea.
  - LOC 18 (folder 4 of 15), 1991 (Box-folder 1/21)
    Map of Papua New Guinea. Text about music in the Eastern Highlands of Papua New Guinea. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands Province, Usarufa.
  - LOC 18 (folder 5 of 15) (Box-folder 1/22)
    Ethnomusicological Report. By Vida Chenoweth for Encyclopedia of World Music. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands Province, Usarufa.
  - LOC 18 (folder 6 of 15), 1958-1971 (Box-folder 1/23)
    Transcriptions of Usarufa Music. Chenoweth, Vida, "Usarufa Songs" and Scripture Songs, Summer Institute of Linguistics. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands Province, Usarufa.
  - LOC 18 (folder 7 of 15) (Box-folder 1/24)
    A Homily of Homonyms, Darlene Bee. Small sheet of linguistics and translations. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands Province, Usarufa.
  - LOC 18 (folder 8 of 15), 1970 (Box-folder 1/25)
    Article by Vida Chenoweth and Darlene Bee, Read (Adult Literacy Magazine). Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands Province, Usarufa.
  - LOC 18 (folder 9 of 15), 1968 (Box-folder 1/26)
    Chenoweth, Vida and Darlene Bee "On Ethnic Music." Practical Anthropology, Sept.-Oct. 1968, 205-212. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands Province, Usarufa.
  - LOC 18 (folder 10 of 15), 1968 (Box-folder 1/27)
    Booklet. Summer Institute of Linguistics "Shaping Tomorrow in New Guinea" Ukarumpa, Territory of New Guinea (Now Papua New Guinea) 1968. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands Province, Usarufa.
  - LOC 18 (folder 11 of 15), 1972 (Box-folder 1/28)
    "Sing a New Song" Ukarumpa High School, Eastern Highlands District, Papua New Guinea. Collection of songs by Ukarumpa High School students, faculty and friends. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands Province, Usarufa.
  - LOC 18 (folder 12 of 15) (Box-folder 1/29)
    Pamphlet. Bee, Darlene and Vida Chenoweth "Translation Begins for the Usarufas." Wycliffe Bible Translators. Santa Ana, CA. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands Province, Usarufa.
  - LOC 18 (folder 13 of 15) (Box-folder 1/30)
    Pamphlet. Darlene Bee and Vida Chenoweth "The Year of the Helicopter." Wycliff Bible Translators. Santa Ana, CA. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands Province, Usarufa.
  - LOC 18 (folder 14 of 15), 1965 (Box-folder 1/31)
    Sound Recording Log. Music of the Usarufa language group. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands Province, Usarufa.
  - LOC 18 (folder 15 of 15), 1967-1971, r67/377, r67/378, r67/379, r67/380, r69/381, r69/382, r68/383, r69/384, r67/391a, r67/391b, r67/392, r69/395, r71/396, r68/397, r68/398 (Box-folder 1/32)
  - LOC 18.1 (folder 1 of 7), 1969-1971, c78/122, c78/791?, r71/128, r71/129, r71/130, r71/131, r71/132, r71/133, r69/134, r69/135, r69/136, r69/137, r71/138, r71/139, r71/140 (Box-folder 1/33)
    Sound Recording Log. Correspondence. Excerpts from the diary of Vida Chenoweth. Correspondence from Doreen Marks to Vida Chenoweth. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands Province, Auyaana-Kosena.
  - LOC 18.1 (folder 2 of 7), r71/128, r71/129 (Box-folder 1/34)
    Kendall, Ron and Kenneth Wolf, song transcriptions. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands Province, Auyaana-Kosena.
  - LOC 18.1 (folder 3 of 7), 1969, r71/130, r71/131, r71/128, r71/129 (Box-folder 1/35)
    Sound Recording Log. Klett, Linda and Sharon Roth--(Illegible) "Auyaana-Kosena Women's and Girls Songs." Titled transcriptions, interval analysis. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands Province, Auyaana-Kosena.
  - LOC 18.1 (folder 4 of 7), 1969, r71/138, r71/139, r71/140 (Box-folder 1/36)
    Barth, Cynthia "Auyana-Kosena." Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands Province, Auyaana-Kosena.
  - LOC 18.1 (folder 5 of 7), r71/138, r71/139, r71/140 (Box-folder 1/37)
    Religious song transcriptions. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands Province, Auyaana-Kosena.
  - LOC 18.1 (folder 6 of 7) (Box-folder 1/38)
    Transcriptions of Scriptural Song Text into the Kosena Language. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands Province, Auyaana-Kosena.
  - LOC 18.2 (folder 1 of 2), 1967 (Box-folder 2/1)
    Chenoweth, Vida "Binumerian,: stylistic features." 5 drafts of report. Includes intervallic analysis, song structure analysis. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands Province, Binumarian.
  - LOC 18.2 (folder 2 of 2), 1966 (Box-folder 2/2)
    Sound Recording Log. Excerpt from the diary of Vida Chenoweth. Includes song text translations and song titles. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands Province, Binumarian.
  - LOC 18.3 (folder 1 of 4), 1984, c84/414 (Box-folder 2/3)
    Sound Recording Log. Music of the Usarufa language group, Eastern Highlands Province of Papua New Guinea.
  - LOC 18.3 (folder 2 of 4), 1960, r60/104 (Box-folder 2/4)
  - LOC 18.3 (folder 3 of 4), 1991 (Box-folder 2/5)
    Video Recording Log. Describes video- recorded events, does not reference a video or film by name or number. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands.
  - LOC 18.3 (folder 4 of 4), 1966 (Box-folder 2/6)
  - LOC 18.4 (folder 1 of 2) (Box-folder 2/7)
    Chenoweth, Vida "Usarufa Songs" Summer Institute of Linguistics. Titled transcriptions. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands, Ukarumpa.
  - LOC 18.4 (folder 2 of 2), 1968-1971 (Box-folder 2/8)
    Sound Recording Log. Song text translations. Music of the Usarufa language group. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands Province.
  - LOC 18.5, 1969-1981, c81/109 (Box-folder 2/9)
    Sound Recording Log. Includes the names of Usarufa composers. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands Province, Usarufa.
  - LOC 18.6, 1968, c67/101 (Box-folder 2/10)
    Sound Recording Log. Excerpt from the diary of Vida Chenoweth. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands Province, Usarufa.
  - LOC 18.7 (folder 1 of 3), 1969, r69/092 (Box-folder 2/11)
    Sound Recording Log. Correspondence. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands, Baruya.
  - LOC 18.7 (folder 2 of 3), r69/092 (Box-folder 2/12)
    Interval analysis, emic analysis, flow charts, titled transcriptions. Report. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands, Baruya.
  - LOC 18.7 (folder 3 of 3), r69/092 (Box-folder 2/13)
    Titled Transcriptions. Monette, Becca "Baruya." Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands, Baruya.
  - LOC 18.8 (folder 1 of 4), 1965-1966, r66/097, r66/096, r65/160 (Box-folder 2/14)
    Sound Recording Log. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands, Gadsup.
  - LOC 18.8 (folder 2 of 4), 1965-1966 (Box-folder 2/15)
    Notes, Gadsup music. Chenoweth, Vida "Song Structure of a New Guinea Highlands Tribe." Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands, Gadsup.
  - LOC 18.8 (folder 3 of 4), 1966 (Box-folder 2/16)
    Article by Vida Chenoweth. Chenoweth, Vida "Song Study of a New Guinea Highlands Tribe" Journal for the Society of Ethnomusicology. September, 1966, 285. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands, Gadsup.
  - LOC 18.8 (folder 4 of 4), 1965-1966 (Box-folder 2/17)
    Excerpts from the Diary of Vida Chenoweth. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands, Gadsup.
  - LOC 18.9 (folder 1 of 2), 1976 (Box-folder 2/18)
    Sound Recording Log. Includes song categories and song text analysis. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands, Agarabi/Kamano/Gahuku.
  - LOC 18.9 (folder 2 of 2) (Box-folder 2/19)
    Stevens, Lucina and Vida Chenoweth "Agarabi." Titled transcriptions. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands, Agarabi.
  - LOC 18.10 (Box-folder 2/20)
    Sound Recording Log. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands, Gahuku.
  - LOC 18.11 (folder 1 of 4), 1966, r66/098 (Box-folder 2/21)
    Sound Recording Log. Collected by Robert and Rosemary Young. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands, Bena Bena language.
  - LOC 18.11 (folder 2 of 4), 1967 (Box-folder 2/22)
    Chenoweth, Vida " Song Style of the Bena Benas." Includes intervallic analysis and song structure analysis. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands, Bena Bena.
  - LOC 18.11 (folder 3 of 4), 1967 (Box-folder 2/23)
    Chenoweth, Vida "Song Style of the Bena Bena." Intervallic analysis, song structure analysis. 3 copies. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands, Bena Bena.
  - LOC 18.11 (folder 4 of 4), 1968 (Box-folder 2/24)
    Correspondence from Via Goroka to Vida Chenoweth. Correspondence. Maps. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands, Bena Bena.
  - LOC 18.12, 1981 (Box-folder 2/25)
    Sound Recording Log. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands, Siane.
  - LOC 18.13 (folder 1 of 2), 1977, c81/150 (Box-folder 2/26)
    Sound Recording Log. Includes song text translation. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands, Siane.
  - LOC 18.13 (folder 2 of 2), 1968-1969 (Box-folder 2/27)
    Correspondence. James, Dorothy "Toward Ethnic Hymnody" Practical Anthropology Jan-Feb 1969, 34-38. Correspondence from D. James to Vida Chenoweth. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands, Siane.
  - LOC 18.14 (folder 1 of 2), 1969-1976 (Box-folder 3/1)
  - LOC 18.14 (folder 2 of 2), r76/118 (Box-folder 3/2)
    Report. Etic and emic transcriptions and interval analysis. Papua New Guinea, Morobe Province, Waffa.
  - LOC 18.15 (folder 1 of 2) 1968-1976, r76/141, r76/142, r77/143, r77/144, r68/145 (Box-folder 3/3)
    Sound Recording Log. Includes song text analysis. Collected by Ron Kendall. Papua New Guinea, Morobe Province, Waffa.
  - LOC 18.15 (folder 2 of 2), r76/141, r76/142, r77/143, r77/144, r68/145 (Box-folder 3/4)
    Report. Titled Transcriptions, Emic Analysis, Emic Transcriptions, Graphic Analysis. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands, Fore.
  - LOC 18.16 (folder 1 of 3), 1968-1976, r69/147, r69/148, c76/149 (Box-folder 3/5)
    Sound Recording Log. Song text analysis. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands, Tairora.
  - LOC 18.16 (folder 2 of 3), 1970 (Box-folder 3/6)
    Etic Transcriptions. Avery, Tom "Tairora" University of Oklahoma. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands, Tairora.
  - LOC 18.16 (folder 3 of 3) (Box-folder 3/7)
    Emic analysis/statement, titled transcriptions. Gabriel, Alison and Rebecca Zavala "Emic Transcriptions of the Tiarora Tribe of New Guinea." Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands, Tairora.
  - LOC 18.17 (folder 1 of 2), 1969 (Box-folder 3/8)
    Sound Recording Log. Song text translations. Correspondence. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands, Asaro.
  - LOC 18.17 (folder 2 of 2) (Box-folder 3/9)
    Numbered transcriptions which may correspond to sound recording r69/146. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands, Asaro.
  - LOC 18.18 (folder 1 of 2) (Box-folder 3/10)
    Sound Recording Log. Collected by Sam McBride. Includes song text analysis. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands, Gimi.
  - LOC 18.18 (folder 2 of 2) (Box-folder 3/11)
    Titled Transcriptions. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands, Gimi.
  - LOC 18.19 (folder 1 of 2), 1969 (Box-folder 3/12)
    Sound Recording Log. Includes song text translations. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands, Kamano.
  - LOC 18.19 (folder 2 of 2) (Box-folder 3/13)
    Transcriptions. Emic Transcriptions. Chenoweth, Vida "The Analysis and Theory of Kamano Song." Includes song structure, song text and interval analysis. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands, Kamano.
  - LOC 18.20 (folder 1 of 2), 1960 (Box-folder 3/14)
    Sound Recording Log. Collected by Darlene Bee. Music of the Usarufa language group. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands Province.
  - LOC 18.20 (folder 2 of 2), 1993 (Box-folder 3/15)
    Article by Vida Chenoweth. Chenoweth, Vida "Lost in Music." Market Place, 1993, 42-44. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands, Usarufa.
  - LOC 18.21 (folder 1 of 3), 1966-1967 (Box-folder 3/16)
    Sound Recording Log. Transcriptions. Sound Recording Log. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands, Awa.
  - LOC 18.21 (folder 2 of 3), 1966-1967 (Box-folder 3/17)
    Song Text Translations. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands, Awa.
  - LOC 18.21 (folder 3 of 3), 1969 (Box-folder 3/18)
    Chenoweth, Vida "An Investigation of Awa Songs." Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands, Awa.
  - LOC 18.22 (folder 1 of 2), 1969 (Box-folder 3/19)
    Sound Recording Log. Includes song text translations and analysis. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands, Kanite.
  - LOC 18.22 (folder 2 of 2), r69/123, r69/124, r69/125, r69/126, r69/127, r63/531 (Box-folder 3/20)
    Titled Transcriptions Interval Analysis. Includes emic transcriptions. Student Work. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands, Kanite.
  - LOC 18.23, 1976, c76/091 (Box-folder 3/21)
    Sound Recording Log. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands, Siane/Bena Bena/Kofena/Yagariaa.
  - LOC 18.24 (folder 1 of 2) (Box-folder 3/22)
    Report. Includes intervallic analysis. Report by Vida Chenoweth contributed to Garland Encyclopedia of World Music. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands.
  - LOC 18.24 (folder 2 of 2), 1976 (Box-folder 3/23)
    Sound Recording Log. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands, Binumarian.
  - LOC 18.25, 1991 (Box-folder 4/1)
    Programs from Aiyura National High School, "Big Day" event. Papua New Guinea, Eastern Highlands, Aiyura.
  - LOC 19, 1992 (Box-folder 4/2)
    Song translation and trascription. Papua New Guinea, Vanuatu, Mota.
  - LOC 19.a, 1994, c94/804 (Box-folder 4/3)
    Recorded by Dan Garst. Papua New Guinea, Vanuatu, Banks Island, Mota village.
  - LOC 19.1, 1995, c95/802 (Box-folder 4/4)
    Sound Recording Log. Includes song text analysis. Recorded by Vida Chenoweth with Dan Garst as interpreter. Papua New Guinea, Vanuatu, Banks Island, Mota village.
  - LOC 19.2 (Box-folder 4/5)
    Report. Includes song categories, interval analysis, song structure analysis and titled transcriptions. Papua New Guinea, Vanuatu, Mota.
  - LOC 19.9a (Box-folder 4/6)
    Titled Transcriptions. Etic transcriptions by Ken Hollingsworth. Papua New Guinea, Agarabi.
  - LOC 20 (folder 1 of 2), 1994-1995 (Box-folder 4/7)
    Research pertaining to Vanuatu. Papua New Guinea, Vanuatu, Tanna Island, Lamakaun village.
  - LOC 20 (folder 2 of 2), 1994-1995 (Box-folder 4/8)